Abbey Bercher, BS

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript programming with a passion for learning and solving problems. Diverse background in the animal industry to include academia and customer service. Skilled in time management and communication that leads to successful technical projects. Excited to combine creativity and critical thinking with technical training to help companies find unique solutions and create quality projects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, Ruby, HTML, CSS

Frameworks and Libraries: Ruby on Rails, React, MUI (Material-UI), Bootstrap, Recharts

Tools: GitHub, Git, Postman, VS Code

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Buck-it, Let's Go Github | Demo

A full-stack application that allows users to create a detailed travel-based bucket list visualized through a map

- Implemented a wrapper to increase the compatibility of Mapbox with React
- Configured a Rails API to work with sessions and cookies to maintain secure user login
- Developed mobile-first with MUI (Material-UI) components to ensure responsiveness among the application
- Planned design and execution using Figma to improve user experience

Wordle Infinite <u>Github</u> | <u>Demo</u>

An enhanced clone of the popular game Wordle, with the added ability to login and play more than once a day

- Implemented authentication and password protection with BCrypt
- Restructured React components for increased organization and readability of code
- Tested for bugs throughout development to minimize issues upon deployment to Heroku
- Optimized mobile experience throughout development resulting in a mobile-friendly application

DataDash (Productivity App)

Github | Demo

A dashboard and suite of tools that provide an organized overview of a user's personal finances

- Utilized Recharts to create charts and graphs that visualized financial data
- Upheld detailed version control and good communication on a team using Git and GitHub
- Designed a JSON-server to create a RESTful API allowing for an efficient backend
- Applied client-side routing using react-router resulting in smooth transitions between components

WORK EXPERIENCE

Bercher Web Development

Feb 2021 – Present

Principal | Web Developer & Designer

Raleigh, NC

- Develop optimized websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and WordPress resulting in client-friendly interfaces.
- Improve SEO, leading to increased site traffic and visibility on multiple projects.

Charles River Laboratories

Jul 2021 - Nov 2021

Animal Care Technician II

Raleigh, NC

- Increased animal production by adjusting the breeding plan to suit the needs of the COVID-19 pandemic
- Oversaw the care and wellbeing of over 1000 animals daily resulting in increased animal welfare

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Remote

Certification – Software Engineering

Nov 2021 – Feb 2022

North Carolina State University

Raleigh, NC May 2020

Bachelor of Science (BS) - Animal Science